A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, International Division, Latin America and the Caribbean, Jamaica and Mexico City Field Office Files FA612
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Reports, 1958-1969; III
  - Venezuela -- Report Re: Establishment of Post-Graduate Institute of Administration, 1964 July (Box 4)
  - Venezuela -- "Evaluation of Universidad de Oriente Possibilities to Develop Eastern Venezuela" by Antonio Bacigalupo, 1964 September (Box 4)
  - Venezuela -- Trip Report (Aug 25-Sep 2, 1964) and Universidad de Oriente by Grover E. Murray, 1964 October 26 (Box 4)
  - Venezuela -- Correspondence/Report Re: Science Project/Oriente-Kansas by B. Leonard, 1965 June 23 (Box 4)
  - Venezuela -- "Report on Consultation with EDUPLAN and Ford Foundation Personnel" by Frederick B. Davis, 1967 August (Box 4)
  - "Written Testimony for the Subcommittee on Government Research of the Committee on Government Operations, United States Senate" by K.H. Silvert, 1967 June 27 (Box 4)
- Subject Files, 1963-1973; IV
  - Administration -- Establishment of Ford Foundation Office in Kingston -- Legal Status, 1964-1970 (Box 5)
  - Administration -- Establishment of Office in Kingston, 1967-1970 (Box 5)
  - Administration -- Ford Foundation, New York -- Insurance Coverage -- Fire, Theft, Accidents, 1966-1970 (Box 5)
  - Caribbean -- Antigua -- General, incl. Donald David's Antigua Speech, 1965-1971 (Box 5)
  - Caribbean -- Bahamas -- General, 1968-1972 (Box 5)
  - Caribbean -- Black Power, Studies, and Race Relations, 1969-1972 (Box 5)
  - Caribbean -- British Ministry of Overseas Development (MOD), 1967-1972 (Box 5)
  - Caribbean -- Caribbean Food and Nutrition Institute (CFNI), 1970-1972 (Box 5)
  - Caribbean -- CARIFTA -- Reports, circa 1969 (Box 5)
  - Caribbean -- CARIFTA, 1967-1971 (Box 5)
  - Caribbean -- Conservation -- Caribbean Conservation Association, incl. booklet on Ford Foundation Grants in Resources and Environment, 1968-1970 (Box 5)
  - Caribbean -- Cuba -- Research on Lower-Class Families in Cuba -- Supplement No. 1, 1972 (Box 5)
  - Caribbean -- Educational Television -- General, 1967-1970 (Box 5)
  - Caribbean -- Ford Foundation Caribbean Program -- Project Data Sheets Binder, 1970 October (Box 5)
  - Caribbean -- Ford Foundation Contributions in Education and Manpower Development, 1970 (Box 5)
  - Caribbean -- Marine Sciences, 1968-1970 (Box 5)
  - Caribbean -- Organization of Caribbean Bar Association, 1971 (Box 5)
  - Caribbean -- Regional Development Bank, 1968-1973 (Box 5)
  - Caribbean -- University of the Netherland Antilles, 1967 (Box 5)
  - Caribbean -- Vocational Education in Eastern Caribbean -- MOD Proposal (L67-447), 1967-1972 (Box 5)
  - Dominican Republic -- Association for Development -- General, 1966-1970 (Box 5)
  - Dominican Republic -- Dominican Fellows Program, 1970-1972 (Box 5)
  - Dominican Republic -- Ford Foundation Dominican Agricultural Program, 1964-1969 (Box 5)
  - Dominican Republic -- Fundacion Dominicana de Desarrollo (FDD), 1969-1972 (Box 5)
  - Dominican Republic -- General, 1964-1970 (Box 6)
  - Dominican Republic -- Political Situation Reports, 1964-1970 (Box 6)
  - Haiti -- Agricultural Program, 1969-1970 (Box 6)
  - Haiti -- General, 1966-1972 (Box 6)
  - Haiti -- Individual Studies/Reports, 1968-1969 (Box 6)
  - Haiti -- Social Sciences -- CHISS -- General and Publication, 1970-1972 (Box 6)
  - Grenada -- General, 1969-1972 (Box 6)
  - Guyana -- University of Guyana -- English Dialect Survey Discretionary Project, 1967-1971 (Box 6)
  - Guyana -- Report on Education in Guyana, 1967 November (Box 6)
  - Jamaica -- Archaeology and Conservation, 1968-1970 (Box 6)
  - Jamaica -- "Brain Drain" study (Jay Buffenmeyer), 1969-1972 (Box 6)
  - Jamaica -- Central Planning Unit, 1966-1972 (Box 6)
  - Jamaica -- Citizens Education Foundation, 1969-1970 (Box 6)
  - Jamaica -- Conference on Education, 1970 (Box 6)
  - Jamaica -- Consultant Report Re: Industrial Relations System and Jamaica Employers' Federation, 1968-1970 (Box 6)
  - Jamaica -- Institute of Management, 1968-1971 (Box 6)
  - Jamaica -- Library Issues Re: UWI and Ford Foundation Field Office, 1963-1968 (Box 7)
  - Jamaica -- Manley Foundation, 1970-1971 (Box 7)
  - Jamaica -- Ministry of Finance and Planning, 1968-1970 (Box 7)
  - Jamaica -- Ministry of Youth and Development, 1967-1971 (Box 7)
  - Jamaica -- Parliamentary Library Proposal and Support, 1968-1970 (Box 7)
  - Jamaica -- Scientific Research Council and Report Re: Science Policy in Venezuela, 1968-1969 (Box 7)
  - Jamaica -- U.S. Embassy and Aid, 1965-1971 (Box 7)
  - Law and Development -- "International Legal Studies Programs Supported by the Ford Foundation, 1951 to Date" -- List of Grants, 1965 (Box 7)
  - Population -- Jamaican Marketing Study (Farley and Leavitt), 1968-1972 (Box 7)
  - Population -- St. Vincent Conference (Windward, Leeward and French Islands and Barbados) (69-1), 1968-1970 (Box 7)
  - Sir Arthur Lewis -- Sabbatical Leave in Barbados, 1971, 1969 (Box 7)
  - Trinidad and Tobago - Committee on Economic Development, 1967-1970 (Box 7)
  - University of the West Indies (UWI) -- Agriculture (PA66-210) -- Reports, Basic Documents, Payments, General Correspondence, 1966-1970 (Box 7)
  - University of the West Indies (UWI) -- Creative Arts Centre (Ref. Humanities and the Arts), 1967-1972 (Box 7)
  - University of the West Indies (UWI) -- Department of Government, 1966-1972 (Box 7)
  - University of the West Indies (UWI) -- Department of Extra-Mural Studies, 1966-1972 (Box 7)
  - University of the West Indies (UWI) -- Faculty of Engineering, 1967-1971 (Box 7)
  - University of the West Indies (UWI) -- Faculty of Law, 1967-1970 (Box 7)
  - University of the West Indies (UWI) -- Faculty of Medicine, 1969-1971 (Box 7)
  - University of the West Indies (UWI) -- Faculty of Natural Sciences (incl. report on science and technology education in Venezuela), 1967-1971 (Box 7)
  - University of the West Indies (UWI) -- General (folder 1), 1966-1967 (Box 7)
  - University of the West Indies (UWI) -- General (folder 2), 1968-1969 (Box 7)
  - University of the West Indies (UWI) -- General (folder 3), 1970-1971 (Box 7)
  - University of the West Indies (UWI) -- Institute of International Relations, 1966-1970 (Box 7)
  - University of the West Indies (UWI) -- Multi-Racial Studies Centre, 1968-1971 (Box 7)
  - University of the West Indies (UWI) -- Social Sciences -- Manpower Planning Project -- ISER (L68-68), 1968-1970 (Box 8)
  - University of the West Indies (UWI) -- PA 68-745/Vol.2 -- Management and Education Recruitment, 1967-1970 (Box 8)
  - University of the West Indies (UWI) -- Trinidad, 1967-1972 (Box 8)
  - University of the West Indies (UWI) -- University Operations Missions (Alexander, Morgan, Stone), 1966-1968 (Box 8)
- Grant and Proposal Files, 1962-1974; V
  - Caribbean -- Association of Caribbean Universities -- UNICA, 1969-1974 (Box 8)
  - Dominican Republic -- Autonomous University of Santo Domingo -- Faculty of Agricultural and Veterinary Sciences (PA65-99), 1967 (Box 8)
  - Dominican Republic -- Texas A&M -- Backstopping Agriculture in the Dominican Republic (PA63-429), 1962 (Box 8)
  - Dominican Republic -- Texas A&M -- Training and Consulting Assistance for SCAD in the DR (64-179), 1963-1969 (Box 8)
  - Education -- UWI Institute of Educatioin (PA62-334), Vol. II -- New Proposals, 1968-1969 (Box 8)
  - Local Travel Award (FY1970) -- Gordon, Shirley, 1969-1970 (Box 8)
  - Population -- Ford Foundation Caribbean (L68-103), 1967-1969 (Box 8)
  - Trinidad -- Manpower Advisor to Trinidad Government -- Ajit Das Gupta (PA70-51), 1971 (Box 8)
  - University of the West Indies -- Demographic Research (PA64-280), 1966-1970 (Box 8)
  - University of the West Indies -- ISER and Census Program (PA69-589, Vol. 2), 1968-1971 (Box 8)
  - University of the West Indies -- Reports -- University Centers -- History -- Economics and Management (folder 1), 1966-1972 (Box 8)
  - University of the West Indies -- University Centers -- Textbook -- History -- Economics and Management (folder 2), 1964-1972 (Box 8)
  - University of the West Indies -- Research in Trinidad in Social Science, 1968-1972 (Box 8)